[ominous music playing]
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
[man] Your Majesty.
Prince Iksang has arrived.
Has his son come as well?
Yes. Your Majesty.
How is Prince Yeongan's health?
[man] There has been no improvement.
so he will not be able to attend
at this time.
-You may leave.
-[man 2] Yes.
[door opens]
[door closes]
It seems that Gu-cheon
has failed his part. Your Majesty.
I've heard people say
the reason I am able to sit on this throne
is due to spirits.
Now they mock me.
saying that my position
will be threatened because of spirits.
Which do you believe to be true?
We will know which one when we get there.
[music fades]
[Jang] Kneel before the honored guest.
straighten yourself.
and perform the four ceremonial bows.
[pressing music playing]
[Jang] Bow.
Straighten.
Bow.
Next. the Crown Prince
would present a ceremonial drink.
praying for your long life
without illness.
However. as the seat is vacant.
I suggest you omit it.
No. That's enough.
This tired and old body
cannot be certain any longer
of another birthday to come.
And what do you think of that.
Your Majesty?
Then you must do as you wish. Mother.
Prince Iksang's eldest son.
will you step forward right now?
[man 1] Prince Iksang. congratulations.
[pressing music continues]
[Jang] This is the drink
presented by Prince Inha.
Your Royal Highness.
I pray for your well-being.
[traditional Korean music playing]
[music stops]
[door rattles open]
[wind whistles]
[man 2] What is happening?
[people murmuring]
[tense music swells]
[tense solemn music playing]
[screaming]
-[wind whistling]
-[sand rustling]
[panicked clamoring]
[Queen gasps]
I can tell
that something has arrived here.
[tense solemn music continues]
[music intensifies]
[King] All right.
I knew that if I drove you far enough.
you would come to me with that resentment.
Now.
what will you do?
[tense dramatic music playing]
[Saeng-gang] Gu-cheon! [gasps]
[bell jingles]
-[unsettling music playing]
-[body thuds]
[panting]
Get a hold of yourself!
You'll become an ak-gwi.
If you kill.
that's what's going to happen to you.
[Saeng-gang whimpers]
You said that becoming
an ak-gwi after death
was what you feared more than anything.
Gu-cheon!
Your mother's death was not your fault.
You must believe that.
[grunts]
[gasps]
You were possessed by the gwi-mae.
[groaning]
If you still won't trust me.
then I'll get to the bottom of this.
The second we can leave the palace.
I will go find your mother's grave
so we can uncover the…
[pained gasps]
[pants]
[sobs] Please. Gu-cheon.
[music fades]
Let us make it out of the palace alive.
[Saeng-gang sobs. pants]
[rhythmic instrumental music playing]
[both breathing heavily]
THE EAST PALACE
[music fades]
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[panicked screaming]
[Iksang] What is wrong with him?
What happened to him? Come on. Wake up!
Send for the physician!
Summon the physician now!
[man 1] Your Majesty.
This child is a little flawed.
[solemn ethereal music playing]
You must be disappointed
with what you're observing. Mother.
In such a frail state.
how could he ever endure
the palace's energy?
I must say you need improving
when reading others. Mother.
Resume the banquet at once.
[man 2] Carry on the music!
[man 1] What are you standing around for?
Attend to Prince Inha at once!
[solemn ethereal music continues]
[gasps. grunts]
[grunting]
[strains]
[stirring string music playing]
[panting]
No. no.
Princess.
Princess!
[Saeng-gang coughs]
[gasps]
[coughing continues]
[breathing heavily]
[music fades]
Have you lost your mind?
I told you to never set foot in there.
You've never listened to me once.
I saved you. and this is the thanks I get.
Am I supposed to do nothing and just
stand by and watch you become a gwi-sin?
You are never
to do something like that again.
whether I am a spirit or not.
I never want to see someone die
because of me again.
[poignant music playing]
[grunts. pants]
I will never do it again
if you truly cannot bear it.
I. too.
cannot convince myself to go in again.
I was terrified.
It must have been very difficult for you.
having spent all that time in there.
[Saeng-gang sighs]
[breathing shakily]
[bell jingles]
[jingling continues]
[distant whispering]
[whispering continues]
[woman] Everyone who carries
the King's blood is mad.
There are no such things as spirits.
Mother.
There are no spirits.
[young Saeng-gang breathing nervously]
Mother?
Your father is the palace entity.
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
How are you?
What are you doing out there?
How is it? Your fever?
Why would you
open the window without asking?
At least you still have your temper.
[door opens]
[Ji-yul] Miss Saeng-gang. you're awake!
How are you feeling now?
What in the world is going on?
I thought Gu-cheon was dead.
Now he's talking to you
and walking around.
And you. who are perfectly fine.
slept for three days and nights.
I mean. you basically slept like the dead.
It was three days?
Yes! Have this first.
I had to beg the female royal physician
to brew this medicine.
and I snuck some rice cakes
to bring to you here.
You haven't eaten one thing
for three days.
Here. please have these.
I appreciate it.
[tender music playing]
But. um. why did you bring me
so many rice cakes?
It's Gu-cheon.
I brought some for him also.
But he just left.
He must have terrible luck with food.
Is he not even hungry?
He has not eaten for three days.
[tender music continues]
Mmm.
[sighs]
After three days without food.
it tastes better.
Do you want some?
I don't have an appetite.
Please help yourself.
You should eat too.
You cannot work without it.
I found something at the guard's house.
I will handle all of that.
You needn't be concerned. Your Highness.
"Your Highness"?
What?
You have changed somehow.
[Gu-cheon groans]
[Saeng-gang sighs]
So. anyway.
tell me what you have found at the house.
I found what the Favored Court Lady
made for the child she was carrying.
Do you think
this could ease her resentment?
It might be possible.
but the preparation will be complicated.
Her spirit is not ordinary.
She killed people
for 30 years as a won-gwi.
Oh! The lightning-struck jujube wood.
Where did you get that?
Ah! The jujube tree
inside the palace was struck by lightning.
-Oh.
-Was that branch helpful at all?
It helped a great deal having that wood.
and it will continue to help.
Well.
I believe I have helped
in more ways than one.
The least you could do is say thank you.
You know. the second you brag.
it makes all of your goodwill disappear?
And how is that bragging?
It is simply the praise I am owed.
I nearly died
dealing with your family's mess.
and you want my thanks and praise?
What? You want recognition that badly?
[scoffs]
[Saeng-gang scoffs]
[both sigh]
Forget it.
Fine. I do not need your thanks.
But you should be thanking
the Ggeomeoksali.
The gwi-mae had you in the well.
and it saved you.
That saved me?
I did wonder why
I had not seen it roaming around here.
It fell into the well
while helping fight the gwi-mae.
How sad.
Good riddance.
Don't be cold about it!
I don't make stupid decisions
like getting attached to it like you do.
Let's just focus on the pond spirit
and how to get rid of it.
[sighs]
[groaning]
Is something wrong?
The truth is…
[ominous music playing]
…when I crossed over to the other side.
I came face-to-face with the pond spirit.
-[spectral scream]
-[grunts]
[Saeng-gang] It clawed my back
and drained my spiritual energy.
[squelching]
But I was able to come back
because you pulled the rope just in time.
-[rope whooshes]
-[spectral scream]
[Gu-cheon] It clawed you?
[ethereal music playing]
What's the matter?
Uh…
The spirit
that consumed your soul down there…
has likely begun
to regain its strength from it.
The curse that had briefly weakened
will grow stronger again.
[man] Your Majesty.
The royal physician
attending Prince Yeongan
says you must prepare
yourself for what is to come.
[music intensifies]
[King] Why?
[ethereal music continues]
[sighs]
Is confronting the spirit
impulsively like this truly wise?
I believe Prince Yeongan won't make it
through the night. most likely.
He's reached his limit
after enduring the curse for so long.
[music fades]
We cannot waste more time.
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[low growl]
[gasps] Sh!
Can you hear it?
That sound?
[low growl]
-[unsettling music playing]
-[water trickling]
[low growl]
[growling continues]
Be careful. please.
I am not saving someone
who will not say thank you.
You're still on that?
[water splashes]
[unsettling music continues]
[baby crying]
[crying continues]
[spirit breathing shakily]
[music intensifies]
[crying continues]
[spirit whispers] My baby.
[dark music playing]
[grunts]
[low growl]
[grunts. gasps]
-[epic music playing]
-[Gu-cheon] You know how to shoot a bow?
[Saeng-gang] Everyone tried to stop me
because I'm a princess.
but I stubbornly insisted
my father teach me.
[Gu-cheon] So you have been peculiar
since you were little.
I will spin thread from the shirt
made by the Favored Court Lady.
and stain it with my blood.
If you wrap this thread
around an arrow and hit the spirit.
it can weaken its resentment.
Here.
When the baby's crying stops.
that is when you shoot.
We must release the resentment born
of being falsely accused.
as well as the grief of losing her child.
[energy thrumming]
[screams]
[grunts]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[high-pitched scream]
[both groaning]
[Gu-cheon] Killing those of royal blood
will not bring you your child back to you.
So release your resentment now.
and go to the afterlife.
Free yourself
from this hell of a palace. now!
[spirit screams]
[tense percussive music playing]
[music fades]
[mysterious ethereal music playing]
[breathes deeply]
[water splashes]
[gasps]
[Gu-cheon breathing heavily]
[exhales sharply]
[panting]
[Jang] Your Royal Highness.
Prince Yeongan has awakened.
[Queen] What?
Are you saying
he's shown signs of improvement?
Not merely signs of improvement.
He is said to have recovered completely.
It seems that the feng shui master
His Majesty had brought in
has eliminated the pond spirit.
[woman] Your Majesty.
Father. I am better. Father.
You are.
[exhales sharply]
[Queen] So he finally put an end
to the curse that lasted 30 years?
But…
that feng shui master…
How did he prove
that the pond spirit is gone?
I am not sure. Your Royal Highness.
In the process of eliminating the spirit.
he must have learned
what the spirit's true identity was.
and now that man knows the secret.
He knows the truth behind how
that lowly wench turned into a won-gwi.
That man must be silenced at once.
[Saeng-gang] The pond spirit
has finally been eliminated. Father.
[music fades]
Yes.
It does seem that way.
I have now completed your orders.
So I am entitled to a reward.
[rattling]
Before that…
[bell jingles]
[serene ethereal music playing]
[young Saeng-gang] Father.
The palace frightens me.
[King] Frightens you?
And who would ever dare
to frighten a princess?
I keep hearing
strange sounds everywhere I go.
Saeng-gang. come over here.
Here. Carry this with you.
And if you do. this bell will drive away
all of those strange sounds
you are currently hearing.
He lives because of you.
Thank you.
[music fades]
I did not do this
to be praised like a child by you.
Very well.
Then the reward you desire.
What would you like?
Allow Gu-cheon the honor
of leaving the palace immediately.
Of course I will allow it. Yes.
And do not harm him at all.
That is my humble request to you.
Your Majesty.
Why are you not packing your things?
I. uh. have nothing worth packing.
I only need the jujube wood.
For someone leaving the palace.
you do not look very cheerful.
It's just…
Something feels wrong.
[Saeng-gang] What do you mean?
Has Prince Yeongan truly recovered?
Is he completely well?
That is what I was told.
How about your wound? How is that?
The pain is gone at least.
What is the matter?
It should not have been destroyed
so easily.
It was a won-gwi
that had killed the princes
of the East Palace for 30 years.
Four of the late King's sons.
and three of the present king's sons.
For a won-gwi that killed seven.
its power was far too weak.
Are you really sure
that the princes
were killed by the pond spirit alone?
If it wasn't the actions of the spirit.
what's responsible?
[Gu-cheon breathes deeply]
I don't know.
I mean. I thought
it would be a life-or-death struggle.
But seeing how easily
it was resolved is making me doubtful.
I must be out of my mind.
Completely out of my mind.
Since you are departing.
will you go to the temple?
As if I would.
I'm honestly
still thinking about where to go.
And what will you do. Your Highness?
Have you found the one responsible
for your mother's death?
There is just one person it could be.
[ominous music stinger]
[Queen] Are you not the daughter
of the banished Third Senior Consort Han?
What brings you all the way here?
I have brought a gift
to celebrate Your Majesty.
for your 70th birthday.
It's quite modest
compared to the other offerings.
You came all this way for nothing. then.
I never once permitted you
to enter the palace.
It was Father that granted permission.
If that's true.
he did so without my consultation?
Your mother was sent away
for committing a crime.
[Saeng-gang] You mean you framed my mother
and drove her out
to cover up the court maid incident
in the salt storehouse.
Because you feared
that if that incident were to be revealed.
the death of the Favored Court Lady
would come to light.
It's the matter tied to the pond spirit.
One Your Majesty
may wish to keep concealed.
[Queen laughing]
So you barge in spouting nothing
but absurd nonsense in front of me.
Your mother was banished.
She was banished
for burying a cursed object
and because she refused to confess--
Is that why
you had my mother killed back then?
[stirring music playing]
Was her begging my father for help
over and over before she died
what brought up the fear
of exposing your buried sins?
And that poor woman's curse
of the serpent's shed skin.
Is it because you were raised so lowly
outside the palace.
or your mother's origins perchance?
You have truly lost your mind. child.
sitting there.
daring to slander me with such delusions!
You may open the gift.
I have recreated the hangwa she received
from the palace the day before she died.
[breathing heavily]
[Saeng-gang] Not only the taste.
but also the ingredients are the same.
You may try it.
[music intensifies]
Who on earth told you lies
about such a story?
I had no hand in your mother's death.
nor in the death
of the Favored Court Lady.
How could you possibly know events
from long ago?
Was it that feng shui master Gu-cheon
who told you all of this?
I should have taught that bastard
the palace's lesson sooner.
That those who dare to spread lies.
here within these very walls.
will soon be dead.
[grunting]
[Gu-cheon groans. pants]
Tell me about the pond ghost
and what you've learned about it.
A ghost?
In a pond?
Are you talking about your grandfather
who drowned in the bath?
[grunting]
[guard] Throw him into the wooden chest.
[Gu-cheon groans]
[Queen] Death is the only fate for liars
in this strict palace.
Just like your mother in the end.
She was put to a stop.
[music subsides]
I remit
those very words to you.
[intriguing music playing]
[Saeng-gang] This is the baby shirt made
by the Most Favored Lady of the Court.
You gave it to the royal guard
and forced him to falsely claim
the child as his own.
-What is this?
-[Saeng-gang] Your Royal Highness.
I know the Favored Court Lady
was smeared by your lies
and how you managed to have
the royal bloodline all but eliminated.
[cackles] The late King's bloodline.
you say?
That lowly maid who decided
she wanted to dance
with a mere royal guard?
[Saeng-gang] Why go that far?
Unlike the other concubines
who received the King's favor.
why did you frame and kill her?
Could it be that you were…
jealous of a mere maid. Your Highness?
[hissing]
[music fades]
Jealous?
Did you say I was jealous?
That I harbored jealousy
toward such a lowborn girl?
She once lived as my family's servant.
I was the one
who allowed her to serve in the palace
as a menial labor maid.
and you think I was jealous?
[screams] Is that what you're saying?
[clattering]
[tense music playing]
Unlike you. I hail from
a noble lineage spanning generations!
For years on end.
I endured
the late King's scorn and neglect
for failing to bear a child for him.
The fact that a lowly maidservant
received His Majesty's love
and could carry his child.
I could not accept it!
[hissing]
I could allow daughters
of the noble households
and their children.
but I could never allow
for that lowly. feeble woman
to carry his child.
[labored] She had to be eliminated
by any means necessary at all.
Is that why you
made all those false claims then?
Yeah!
I had that slut tortured.
then I myself killed the filthy blood
that continued to grow inside her!
[hissing]
[gasps. groans]
Your Majesty.
-[music subsides]
-[Queen groaning]
I heard you clearly.
Your confession
that you killed the Favored Court Lady
and eliminated the King's son.
[breathes heavily]
What? What?
I will make this public
before Father and all the other ministers.
-[tense solemn music playing]
-[groans]
[Saeng-gang] You stated to me earlier
that liars meet
their timely death in the palace.
Tell me. Your Royal Highness.
what would death mean to you?
It would be losing the palace
and everything that defines you.
[coughing]
[Saeng-gang]
The home you have lived in all your life.
The power you've enjoyed for many years.
I'll make sure it's all gone.
[breathing shakily]
[Jang] Your Majesty.
[Queen growls]
And what could someone like you
possibly do?
Who would ever believe the words
of a lowborn expelled from the palace?
Who?!
That much I know.
Who would listen to the mere words
of the lost princess?
[gasps]
[music intensifies]
Your Majesty. I believe your voice
was loud enough for everyone to hear.
Now.
the time has come
for you to kill these women
the same as you did before.
You will need a lot of jars
for their bones.
[Sukbin] Let us go.
[music soars]
[Queen groans]
[music swells]
-Your Majesty!
-[Queen groans]
-[grunts]
-Your Majesty!
[Gu-cheon groaning]
-[Gu-cheon panting]
-[tuts]
[man 1] I cannot keep
my eyes off you for a second.
Why are you lying in there.
beaten to a pulp?
[Gu-cheon grunts]
What trouble did you cause today
to make Her Majesty want you dead?
Was it not ordered by the King?
To see if I'm capable
of keeping my mouth shut or not?
Since you believe that.
it would be pointless
to mention that is not true.
[unsettling music playing]
[Gu-cheon] Then why do you spare me?
The princess earnestly… pleaded
with His Majesty
to let you leave the palace unscathed.
She must have foreseen
something like this.
This is your pass to leave the palace.
-[pass thuds]
-[coins jingle]
And your compensation.
[coins thud]
Watch your mouth out there.
All eight provinces of Joseon
lie in the hand of His Majesty.
[grunts]
[music fades]
They do not let me go easily.
[women chattering indistinctly]
Still. it's over now.
[purring]
[Gu-cheon] Ah…
[purrs. chomps]
[low grumble]
[chomping. exclaims]
[door hinge squeaks]
-[hissing]
-[ominous music playing]
-[exclaims]
[hissing continues]
[exclaims]
[grunting]
-[squealing]
-[hissing]
[tense music playing]
I saw nothing.
Nothing at all. I did not see anything.
[Ggeomeoksali squeals]
[exhales sharply]
Ah no!
-[music intensifies]
-[squealing continues]
[Gu-cheon straining]
[hissing]
[Gu-cheon groans]
-Whoa. whoa.
-[Ggeomeoksali squeals. purrs]
[music fades]
[Ggeomeoksali purrs]
[Gu-cheon] I have repaid the debt
I owed you for saving me.
So take care.
[Ggeomeoksali chitters. squeals]
-[squeals]
-[tense music plays]
[squealing sigh]
[music fades]
-[whimsical music playing]
-[sighs]
I'll give you a bit of my yang energy.
Just enough for your body to recover.
[purrs]
[sucking]
Get off!
Let go!
Don't take too much. damn it.
That's enough!
[squeals]
[groans]
[panting]
[groaning]
[music fades]
[horse grunts]
[King] You do not look well.
Perhaps you are ill?
It's been hard on me. I think.
working alongside Gu-cheon lately.
And considering the part you played
at the Queen Dowager's quarters
last night.
it makes perfect sense.
And the Queen Dowager.
do you plan to do anything about her?
Is that why you wanted to talk
this early in the morning?
No.
I wanted to make sure
Gu-cheon made it out all right
and is free of the palace.
You fret too easily.
He will have left the palace by now
and surely will have traveled far already.
After all. he saved my son.
I have no desire to hurt Gu-cheon.
He saved my child from death.
Do not be worried.
I must say. though.
I did not expect him
to deal with the pond spirit so easily.
Indeed. Father.
Even Gu-cheon felt strange about it.
He questioned whether it was truly
the pond spirit that killed the princes.
Father…
[unsettling music playing]
…I want to know about the late King's
first son. the Crown Prince.
How exactly did he pass away?
[unsettling music intensifies]
[guard 1] Your Royal Highness!
[guards clamoring]
[guard 2] Your Royal Highness!
-[panting]
-[guard 3] Summon the physician!
The physician!
[breathing shakily]
[guard 2] The Crown Prince…
Your Royal Highness.
[unsettling music continues]
[exhales]
A curse.
He passed away
because a spirit had cursed him.
What of the late King's second son?
[King] A spirit killed him.
The third and fourth brothers as well.
All four of them.
[Gu-cheon] Are you really sure
that the princes
were killed by the pond spirit alone?
What is the matter?
Your Majesty.
The hunting preparations are complete.
Prince Yeongan is waiting for you.
[King] Very well.
[breathing shakily]
We will continue this later.
[music swells]
[spectral voices whispering]
[Saeng-gang panting]
[spectral voices continue]
[music intensifies]
[Saeng-gang pants]
[exhales sharply]
[King] We cannot allow him
to learn the truth of the pond spirit.
-[Saeng-gang] Stop. I don't wanna hear it.
-[man] You do not need to know either.
[Saeng-gang] I do not want
to know any more. [pants]
Please. someone…
[Jang] …admitted to the crime…
-[Saeng-gang] Help me.
-Your father is the palace entity.
[screams]
[music swells]
[gasps]
[music subsides]
Why are you crying?
More importantly.
why haven't you left yet?
There's one thing I didn't see.
The spirit that cursed Prince Yeongan
was not the Favored Court Lady.
The one that tore
your body and soul was not her.
There's got to be another.
Then. um…
[dramatic music playing]
…who was the one that tried to kill
Crown Prince Yeongan?
[breathing heavily]
[music intensifies]
[squelching]
[man] I will have my revenge.
The King
must pay for the sins
that he has committed.
The secrets of
the royal house will be revealed.
And I…
I will become the real one.
I will wipe out the royal bloodline!
[dramatic music continues]
[coughs]
-[squelching]
-[screams]
[screaming]
-[spectral scream]
-[grunts]
-[exhales]
-[squelching]
[spectral screaming]
[Saeng-gang moaning]
[groaning]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[dramatic percussive music playing]
[spectral voices echoing]
[both panting]
Prince Yeongan.
We need to go find Prince Yeongan!
Wait.
It's already too late.
[music subsides]
[epic music playing]
[horse neighs]
[guard 1] Is there a royal physician
back there?
[guard 2] Send for the royal physician!
Take formation.
[guard 1] Stay calm. everyone.
Don't break formation.
[guard 3] Secure the perimeter.
-What's happening?
-[guard 4] Protect His Majesty!
Then you should leave the palace
through this path.
You must run away now.
Since you were unable to save his son.
he will find you and kill you immediately.
But if I leave you behind.
you will die the same as Prince Yeongan.
-[gasps. exhales]
-[music subsides]
-That is a matter beyond your concern.
-It does concern me.
You saved my life.
You risked everything
coming to the other realm to save me.
and now this time.
I'll be the one who is going to save you.
[epic music continues]
[music fades]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm